Hossam El-Bahrawy

Result oriented iOS software engineer with a Bachelor's degree in Computer Engineering and 3 years of professional experience in developing full-stack web and iOS mobile applications, always eager to learn new topics, technologies.

Seeking a new challenging iOS software engineer opportunity.

Cairo, Egypt

- **L** +20 1154881441
- hossamelbahrawy52@gmail.com
- **in** <u>LinkedIn/Hossam-Bahrawy</u>
- GitHub/Hossam-Elbahrawy

WORK EXPERIENCE

Solutions by Stc — *iOS Software Engineer (Full-time)*

June 2022 - PRESENT

MyFleet App— iOS App [<u>Link</u>]

Helping organizations manage their fleet operation, that includes real-time tracking, speed tracking, alerts and notifications.

Built using: UIKit, Alamofire, Realm and GoogleMaps

• MyFleet Admin— Flutter App

Built for MyFleet system admins to speed up the process of managing different customers' vehicles, devices and inventories.

Built using: Flutter, Dio, Provider

School Bus Driver App— iOS App [<u>Link</u>]

Empowering drivers to easily view and live track their assigned trips, kids' absence status, and communicate with parents.

Built using: SwiftUI, Alamofire and HereMap

School Bus Parent/Student App— iOS App [Link]

Helping parents track their children's trips to/from school. With notifications upon bus arrival, departure, route updates.

Built using: SwiftUI, Alamofire and HereMap

Koinz — iOS Software Engineer (Full-time)

Jul 2020 - Jun 2022

Koinz App — iOS App [<u>Link</u>]

Online food & beverage ordering mobile app that currently operates in Egypt, Saudi Arabia and UAE.

- Establishing and implementing a complete design system from scratch
- Enhancing code quality adding SwiftLint to the codebase
- Running experiments using Firebase Remote Configs and A/B Testing.
- CI/CD using AppCenter and testFlight for testing and release
- Monitoring releases with various tools to early detect and fix production and usability issues.

SKILLS

UIKit - SwiftUI - RxSwift - XCTest -SwiftLint - Alamofire - Moya - Realm - FacebookSDK - Google Maps SDK -Here Map SDK - Amazon Payment SDK (PayFort SDK) - Hyperpay SDK -Authorize.Net

Flutter - Dio -Provider - Flutter Lints

OOP - MVC- MVVM - Design Patterns - Design System - Unit Testing - Version control (GIT)

Firebase Remote Config -Firebase A/B
Testing - Firebase Analytics - Firebase
Crashlytics - Firebase Events - App
Center CI/CD - App Center Analytics App Center Diagnostics - Smartlook Amplitude - WebEngage

Jira - ClickUp - Opsgenie - Zeplin -Figma - Notion

LANGUAGES

Arabic: Native **English**: Advanced

German: A1

Built using: UIKit, RxSwift, Moya, Realm and GoogleMaps

Haya Solutions — Full Stack Engineer (Full-time)

Apr 2019 - Aug 2020

• The family sale — E-Commerce Platform

Platform for an internal mega online sale for L'Oreal Egypt employees. The site revenue was estimated to be **+3 Million** EGP

Built using: ReactJs, Material-UI, PaySky

Netjeek — E-Commerce Platform (Frontend) [<u>Link</u>]

Libya's first shopping platform along aside an admin portal Built using: **ReactJs**, **Material-UI**, **ChartJs**

NACG — Asset Management System (Frontend)

Asset management for NACG (North American Construction Group):

Built using: ReactJs, Material-UI, FeathersJs Client, Socket.io

EDUCATION

Faculty of Engineering, Tanta University — Bachelor of Engineering in Computer and Automatic Control

Class of 2019 with grade: Very Good

Graduation Project [Link]: Autonomous Robotic System capable of delivering products ordered from an E-commerce system or a cross-platform mobile application Android or iOS (supported by Valeo Egypt).

Built using: Robotic Car - Nvidia Jetson - Arduino - Raspberry Pi - LIDAR sensor - ROS - ReactJs - SemanticUI - React Native - NodeJs - ExpressJs - MongoDB.